bring friends welcome welcome to the I
see on LASIK for the general
ophthalmologist we intend to cover all
the topics from evaluation to the
procedure complication and how to manage
your refractive practice professor Coker
has talked in another hall so we are
just changing the order a bit I invite
him to talk on smile first Thank You
Shashi good morning everybody
I think this hall is going to be full
with refractive refractive and more
refractive so there's so many ways you
can skin the cat but what is the best
way is what you feel comfortable with
you can buy machines technology comes in
at it's come as a cost you can buy
smiles you can buy fem toes but if
you're not convinced in what you're
doing you can never convince the patient
that this is the best for you so I'll be
sharing with you my experiences file for
the last we have it for last three years
now okay so what exactly is smile
initially when you started LASIK what
came first the egg or the hen I think
the the excitement machine came first so
we started zapping the corneal surfaces
your wires are lose everything so he
started cutting the surface of like a
PRK then we got the blades we got a hank
of blades all these handsaw toms and
anymore yes and all so you raise a flap
like an ambassador car you open the
bonnet treat the engine and you put it
back so you got a flap and you put it
back then came the evolution when you
hit the femtoseconds no femtosecond did
a corneal flap making which was very
precise as compared to the blades so
your standard deviation was about plus
minus 20 microns which was fantastic
because the blades were unpredictable so
once they got a hang off cutting the
cornea in one single plane then the
second thought came why not cut anterior
and posterior both and take a lenticular
out rather than cutting it all around
360 degree and making the cornea weak so
the flap and zap has become flap and
flap only so you cut too
then complete lenticular and take it out
so you have to buy one machine only all
right so the first people who started
this was the it was secundus in which he
created a flap but he lifted the
lenticular dire lenticular from a big
incision it was actually creating a flat
360-degree almost then bloom it all came
to smile and which the incision went to
2 millimeters now everybody in smile is
actually using 2 millimeter incision so
what is good if you cutting more cornea
the two basic things which are happening
in in refractive surgery when you do on
the cornea is you making this cornea a
week for life every procedure in the
cornea when you cut any amount of
collagen will make it weak so which one
is a lesser evil is what you can pick up
both are even right so lesser reveal is
is the one which is smile because you're
not cutting 360 degree so the no
innovation is much better in these ones
the strength of the cornea is there it
definitely becomes weaker than the
pre-operative eyes in both scenarios but
this paper from often all details are
that it's it's much better much safer
for people who have thinner corneas in
which you can still take a chance with
the smile as compared to LASIK ok the
second is the dry eye when you cut the
nerves 360 degree the the biggest thing
you're causing is that all the
innovation has gone down so in this
study they found out that the dry eye is
definitely less in case of smile patient
check that one month six months and one
year follow-up there was a meta-analysis
which the five studies were taken care
in which they compared the dryness in
both the groups and they came to the
conclusion that yes the dry eye is
definitely less in these patients and
all the fibrin score niall nerves are
well preserved in these patients as
compared to this blessing so lassic is
what is a basic talk here you must do
last six also but if you can take a step
up and you can just go to smile but
smile also has its own problem the cost
and the complication which I will be
discussing in sometime so basically that
this step what you do in this one is you
cut the posterior lenticular site cut
anterior lenta cool and incision you
take it out of the eye I'll just you
show a little video here I think that
will clarify everything alright so
that's the blinking light
so there is no infrared capture in this
size so you have to make sure the eyes
in the center and what I did was I put
the infrared on so the infrared on you
can see the pupil which you can't see
otherwise and it's all centered and you
start firing now this is a posterior cut
it's a lenticular post real entacle cut
which is has to take place first because
if you cut the anterior one you can't
cut posterior because the light is not
going to go through the capacity which
are you created where the bubbles so
that's the posterior cut first and then
the side cut and then comes the anterior
one so anterior can do-we can be done
easily because the interior fibers are
still clear and this goes about 0.5
beyond the previous cut and that's the
incision or so that's about it now
everything is cut no you have to go
inside split it up and this was my first
surgery of smile which I did so this is
actual recording it's not been edited at
all
so whatever thing I'm doing a fumbling
or whatever this is what the weight is
so people say it's a bad luck it's a
long learning curve I don't believe that
if you're a average cataract surgeon you
can manage it very well so I'm going
very slowly gingerly so do you cut it
from the posterior and interior when you
dissect you that's it from anterior to
posterior so you're dissecting the
interior plane first
and once you dissect to the interior
then you make a posterior a little flap
on the posterior not all the way and
this is going to take little time
because this was the first surgery which
I operated so I just wanted to show you
the first one have been done about more
than thousand now we take even I think
less than 50% of this time which we are
doing there okay so once you've gone
anterior then you go posterior in that
one and if you notice my lenticular is
going to be free from all the sides and
you just hold it and take it out all
right so you can see the lenticular it's
clear from all the sides no it's it's
been separated from all the same so you
just hold the lenticular it takes it
take it out so learning curve there but
yes the most important thing is the
patient's cooperation if the patient is
cooperative and I was not holding the
eye in this surgery so most of my
fellows who start I tell them to hold
eyes properly and do it gradually over a
period if you develop confidence as the
patient is good you can do without
holding and this is what it looks like
so
so this was a patient with a with a
lesyk and that's the patient with a
smile a minute after the surgery so what
are the shortcomings of this one when
the smile came they never had a good
connection for the cylinder but last
year in October they have started giving
a cylinder till minus three so so you
can do a from minus one to minus 10
depending on what is the residual will
sickness and pre-op workup for smile is
the same as the Lessing it's not having
advantage there so whatever patient you
can do a lastic on you can do a smile
also rights I'm sure lots of people are
going to be talking about smile lesyk so
I'm going to skip that one ectasias can
be seen with PR keys with LASIK as well
as smile so even the smile is going to
make your cornea weak so pick up the
lesser evil is what I said so you're all
residual bit but thickness and pts
should be taken care of in this one the
complication could be two one the
patient is not cooperative so he moves
the eye and the suction ring loses the
suction
second you firing the beam but it's not
cutting the cornea because something
comes in between it could be a mucous on
the eye a dry cornea so at that spots
you'll get dark spots and that's where
the cornea is still sticking to each
other so you don't it will be difficult
to dezik so I'll just show you some
videos and these ones and then we'll
finish it off now see these are the
patients done they look horrible because
they'll come on yeah so you see there's
a struggle going on there L&T goal has
been held from the side and only the
half linty will come out see it's not a
complete lenticular so you go back again
hold it and take it now this video is
one of the worst surgeries I've seen but
the result next day was patient at six
six so you can go back and take it out
the lenticels so there's no point in
leaving the lenticels behind you can
pick it up and if you have a OCT guided
microscope you can do it very easily on
the same day also so once that's taken
care of that's gone you can have suction
loss and the beginning of the surgery or
at the end of the surgery so this is
what happens suction loss
now suction losses is more in these
patient that came to the elastic because
the suction amount of suction pressure
is low in smile patients come on
ah I got no time because I got anyway so
now this is what you see a black spot
here so that is where the cornea is not
dissected yet so when you splitting the
cornea you have to be little more crude
here you have to be little with the with
a little force here to push it open and
do it so we got about a thousand eyes
for now is the basic minimum I have done
is minus 1.5 to 1.75 12 minus 9 at one
week all these patient was 6x6 in the
early phase we use higher energy in
these months and we were getting more of
OB ELLs and and it was taking recovery
time was little longer but now mostly
this patient first day they're 6x6
because energy have been introduced so
suction loss was seen in few patients
and the black spots are seen in few
patient which which which i think is
part of the learning curve and
eventually this all settles down so
shortcoming of the software is that they
don't have a one-way limited incision in
fact in some time they might have to one
millimeter incision and you can split
cornea all around they don't have a OCT
as such on the machine so you might have
to take the patient to the other
microscope sometime if the LNT girl is
left behind the foot control is not
there for the zoom so every time you
have to zoom you have to use the hand
back the with the knob so if you're
doing a procedure you leave the
instrument go to the microscope adjust
the focus again and go back so that's a
little cumbersome so with the request
settings eyes people have put foot
pedals on these machines now so to
conclude the smile is a simple there was
no loss of vision vision any of these
patients and it's predictable and there
was no regression and all these patient
at the end of one year the dryness and
the and the recess and the hysteresis
was pretty good in these patients so
it's quite a safe procedure thank you
very much thank you dr. koker if you
have a question you can leave in the
belt a question later on so because
you're learning okay fine yeah thank you
we now start with first evaluating a
patient who comes for Lacey dr. Savage
gravel from Chandigarh is part of dr.
Grable's
group we have a largest refractive
practice in North India and I'm looking
forward to your talk
Sartaj on evaluating the patient thank
you sir
it's a good morning everyone I would
like to thank my doctor thanking dr.
Shashi Kapoor for giving me the
opportunity to be a part of this
instruction course today let's learn the
approach to interpreting corner
topography and hakama tree now it's
important to remember that both of these
they are the foundation for a successful
refractive surgery and a happy patient
with a stable cornea in the future near
three different techniques for
determining corneal topography the first
and oldest is Placido based and began
with the Placido disc and was followed
with the video creato scope the next is
the slit scanning system utilizing the
ops can as a combination of split
scanning and procedure imaging the third
and most popular used today is the
comment is the shine flow based devices
which will be the pentagram the series
and the Galilei now the information that
these modern topographers provide us is
overwhelming and it can be very easy to
just get lost in the maze that is
created by all this information so it's
very important to narrow what you want
to look at so let's start by just
looking at the four map refractive
display that these machines give you
start off by looking at the elevation
maps the pack limit remap the Anteaters
the sagittal curvature map you need to
look at the carat AMA tree values for
the front and the back surface of the
cornea you need to look at the corneal
thickness data that comes out and some
of the data related to anterior chamber
it's important to adopt a strategy to be
able to browse and analyze this
information in an efficient manner so
first it foremost is always identify the
the report that you are looking at is
for the correct patient it's a very
simple thing but sometimes it can lead
to a lot of mismanagement the next you
need to confirm the quality of
specification now this specifies the
quality of the data that has been
captured it should be a white box with
okay otherwise there is some missing
information which has been extrapolated
by the machine and will be shown in a
yellow box or a red box if this is the
case it is ideal to try and capture the
data once again by repeating the scan
next we look at the Packham a tree the
pupil centers the corneal thickness
which is corresponding to the pupil
center location and it's coordinates are
important to evaluate angle Kappa and
normally the x-coordinate should be less
than point two millimeters which
corresponds to less than five degrees
the pocky apex represents the thickness
at the apex of the cornea and the
computer considers the apex as the
origin of the coordinates the thinness
location of the tent which is the
location of the thinnest point of the
cornea and the difference between the
thinnest location and packy apex
normally will be less than 10 microns
and the y-coordinate is the one that is
important to look at and it's most often
normal when it is less than 0.5
millimeters but if it's between 0.5 and
1 it will be very suspicious and if it's
more than 1 then it is quite abnormal
now compared with ultrasound perimetry
which measures thickness at only one
point the Panda cam can generate 50
thousand data points to describe the
true thickness and a normal packet rehab
will a map will always have a concentric
shape next let's look at K max which is
the maximum curvature power of the whole
anterior surface of the cornea and is
expressed in the Aptus a value of below
47 is suitable for refractive surgery
and a value between 47 and 49 can still
be considered but it is a moderate risk
factor next we look at the Q value which
is defined as the radial change from the
center to the periphery of the corneal
surface and it reflects the corneal
shape and the optical properties
including the refractive power the
spherical aberrations and the aberration
distribution and a normal value will be
anything between minus 1 to 0 looking at
the interior curvature map which
represents the interior surface taptic
power measured by the sagittal method
and one of the normal patterns which can
be seen here is the symmetric board hi
but there are a number of different
patterns that can be observed on this
now it's also important to understand
the settings for the machine and when
you when you want to choose these it's
important to remember that 0.25 step as
can be seen all the way on the Left can
lead to a lot of noise while a wonder of
this step can lead
to wash out of all the details and you
can miss a lot of information so a
half-day after staff has step has been
suggested as the ideal value that best
represents all the information we need
coming to elevation based tomography now
while the procedure imaging is very
useful for determining the surface
corneal curvature elevation is what
helps us understand determine the
overall corneal shape and the spatial
thickness profile now in order to make
this data that we get clinically
relevant we need to compare it against
something and we usually will compare it
against a bet a best-fit sphere and
which is constructed by fitting the
reference here a surface as smoothly as
possible to the data surface as can be
seen in this diagram when we look at the
elevation maps of the cornea we can
again we can see a symmetric hourglass
pattern we can see certain tongue-like
in extensions or irregular patterns
which should be matters of caution the
elevation map has a color scale where
anything interior to the best-fit sphere
is in red anything proceeded to it is in
blue normal values will be anything less
than 12 microns but when anything
between 13 to 15 is suspicious and
anything more than 15 will be a risk
factor and the difference between the
front and the back services should
ideally be less than 5 microns if a
patient has a karateka bonus on a
best-fit sphere we will see it as a
conical protrusion because it'll be
above for the best fit sphere
another great feature to some of the
modern demographers are differential
maps which can help us track the
progress of this patient from scan to
scan and we can easily compare them to
on the same screen next we come to the
Belen ambrosio enhance sick teaser
display which is an excellent tool for
identifying patients who are at risk of
fact Asia and the best part is that it
gives the information in a very colorful
display which are very easy to pick up
its lesser chances that you'll miss
anything that is irregular now the first
two sine elevation maps that come they
display the baseline relative elevation
of the cornea to the best fits here
below them are the anterior and
posterior exclusion maps these are
enhanced elevation maps which display
elevation data with the best fit sphere
calculated using all the raw elevation
data
located outside
a 4-millimeter circle which is centered
on the thinnest point of the cornea next
we come to the D value which takes five
different indices taking into account
the variation in the front surface the
back surface the packing metric
progression the thinnest point and the
thinnest point displacement and it takes
all of these five parameters and then
performs the regression analysis against
the standard database of normal and
katakana guys any value less than one
point six the Optus is normal anything
between one point six and two point six
is a little suspicious and anything
about two point six is abnormal and it's
shown to have a very high sensitivity
and specificity specificity for picking
up patients with keratoconus and Activa
the thickness profiles that are provided
the cornea taking a spatial profile
it describes the average progression of
thickness starting from the thinnest
location to the corneal periphery and
the percentage thickness increase is the
percentage progression of the CTSV
we need to look at the red line which is
the data for the patient that you're
examining and ideally it should follow
the curvature of the black dotted lines
that are there the akhator corneas they
will thin out and they will change the
curvature more rapidly as they go from
the center to the periphery of the
cornea and that is it's very useful to
help differentiate this between just
what is a normally normal thin cornea
and an actual Ecstatic cornea average
values between 0.8 and 1.1 are normal
anything above 1.1 is suggestive of
atactic disorders
so a quick slope like this is suggestive
of fact attic disorders and must be
cautioned the Ambrogio the a the
ambrosial relation thickness values this
is a concept that combines the thinness
PACA mitra values with the packet
redistribution and this facilitates
again the identification of an abnormal
cornea from just a normal thin cornea
and ideally it should be over 400
microns for patients to be suitable and
considered for refractive procedures so
let's just discuss a few cases so again
we'll go step by step we look at the
quality of the scan which is okay we
look at the Packham entry values which
appear good in this case along with the
coordinates the Q value for loose falls
in a normal range the pattern on the
Indian
the interior curvature is normal the
calamity values are within a normal
range and here elevation is normal the
seer elevation is normal the bad display
is also good so this would be a suitable
case for refractive surgery next we come
to a patient another patient and again
the quality of the scan is okay but the
thickness of the cornea is it's quite
thin especially the thinness location is
again there's a significant deviation
also in the coordinates which should be
automatically a red sign for us although
the Q value in this case is normal but
the even the interior curvature if you
look at it we can see a claw pattern
over there we even the K max in this
case is forty eight point six the
interior elevation is twenty-eight four
see the elevation is 47 and even the bad
display is giving an index of seven
point four one so this patient quite
clearly has keratoconus and should be
counseled for CTR but sometimes you can
have cases like these which are not
quite so obvious neither here neither
there again the quality is okay the
Packham III is within normal range the Q
value is okay the interior curvature is
a symmetric border it's just against the
rule but if you look at the spatial
thickness profile it does tend to sort
of fall away steeply as we go towards
the periphery the K max is 47 which is
borderline interior elevation is again
normal the proceeded elevation is
showing an irregular pattern the AR T
values are lower which again should be a
little bit of caution maybe this is a
patient where you want to consider
combining ac3 are along with the rel
factor procedure or at least counseling
the patient that he said may be a
slightly higher risk than normal
coming to pack a meat-free they're
basically two techniques
there's optical documentary and there's
also some documentary in optical you
have shine flow xsplit scanning SOC t
and specular microscopy
all the different techniques that are
useful vacuum Utley they show a very
high correlation and it's probably best
to just use the same machine you use for
topography to also obtain your Packham
entry values always remember measure
twice cut once
thank you
dr. gray values the Turkish which you
are shown if the age of the patient was
50 years or 45 years what will you
consider because most of these patients
they have a fairly good resistance to
develop the keratoconus yes but at 4550
I mean the what I'm considering for a
factor surgery will be very different
I'll have to look at is the leg is the
patient looking at some kind of a
correction but yes all the patients
you're right there is a natural
cross-linking that is occurring they
will be stable the second thing is will
you keep the epital mapping along with
that especially the older patients most
of them have a normal epithelial cells
recently all the suspected cases which
are of the 40 plus even though he's
showing the Quranic pattern they have a
normal epithelial cells and three of
these patients we did a PRK at present
here the 3p arc Avengers waiting how
long how dare you because patella
mapping I person if it's a very
sensitive thing is 40 are you saying
that it should have been abnormal if it
was really keratoconus the epithelial
mapping even if it is harmful
keratoconus will get the sensitivity
first from the epithelial the early
thang before even you can see something
like that thank you thank you so touch
for an excellent presentation on x
because of to our sisha will be i've
requested him to talk to us he's more of
a scientists in spite of being one of
the largest refractive and cataract
surgeons in cataract multifocal he has
done about 12,000 and but a scientist
basically he's done a lot of work on
depth of focus mainly related to the
aisles but i feel it has a lot of role
because of the change of cornea that we
produce you know it does alter the
spherical aberration and i've requested
him and he'll tell us something about
depth of focus to share the depth of
focus how to do right this is probably
the first step in the world where we are
neutralizing the other factors which are
responsible for depth of
and recently I started applying into my
LASIK patients we need about 30 patients
it's a very initial stage of telling
something about whether is working or
not but I'm very very very positive
about the approach which I had but they
have to focus the definition is they
have to focus the lens optic concept
which includes cornea as well as the
lens that measures the tolerance of
placement of image plane in relation to
the lens for us it's a clarity of vision
of the various focusing plane without
changing the position of the eye
especially for Nia the factors which are
contributing for the depth of focus is
size of the pupil aberrations it's a
very small contribution as far as the
oil is concerned but it's going to be
have a very large contribution as far as
the Lessing is concerned and the design
of the eye I started the depth of focus
mainly for multifocal lenses and then I
thought that if you can measure some
good depth of focus to find out and
evaluate the quality of this lenses he
went through the same lenses one batch
is good the second batch is not so good
so if you do this they have to focus all
of us will be able to detect the best
eye well available as far as a
multifocal and trifocals are concerned
and the new eat-off lenses which are
available in the market recently I
studied 300 patients on our PD scan
three the pupil size is approximately
four millimeter in photopic and six
millimeter in the scotopic condition in
a younger patient especially less than
30 years of old it is one millimeter
less in older patient especially 60-plus
this is the data of the Indian
population the smaller the pupil it adds
to depth of focus and needs to be
illuminated to find out the actual
performance of an IO L in depth of focus
studies not done so far all the aisles
and the LASIK patient especially the
bifocal lead-off trifocal very focal
gives a good range of depth of focus at
present when the pupil size is small so
these are the factors which are very
important one of them is spherical
aberrations a small amount of area
collaboration if you leave it behind
either in lasik or in cataract surgery
improves the depth of focus
significantly
always under correct the spherical
aberration is for agile serger is
concerned contribution to the depth of
focus is minimum so it was not included
when I did my studies in Iowa but it is
very much included when I did I started
with the less equations the depth of
focus is done for distance remember if
we always do for distance with undiluted
as well as the dilated pupil as far as
the oil is concerned for the best with
best corrected for distance the size of
the pupil is measured with dilated and
run dilated conditions in a dark room
with OPD scan three the depth of focus
is measured between plus from plus 2 to
minus eight half the outer difference
the graph is plotted on the same paper
dilated as well as unrelated to compare
between the two all the measurements are
done for distance and by changing the
head to the distance correction this
will tell us how much activity of vision
for different add there by how much the
idle can tolerate or even the less
equations it is assumed that the results
of distant depth of focus is more or
less the same as near recently I started
developing something for the near also
we are almost in the end of the study so
we will have something where we were
able to find out the depth of focus for
near call so we check the depth of focus
for near by changing that that is what I
told down I match the depth of focus for
distance and near they are more or less
the same so even if you are doing for
distances almost works same for the near
also this is once one of the bifocal
lens which made by the Indian company
the red one is undiluted in the dilated
so by doing these things you are
neutralizing the effect of the small
pupil as well as so the lens is working
so well in the maintain the depth of
focus fairly well this is another
patience which is most consistent this
is made by an Indian company you see
something which is going up here the
depth of focus is so good because the
light distribution has been extremely
good for distance and it is maintained
for intermediate as well as the nearly
this is the same thing which also you
can find out on a point straight
functions how good quality of the vision
which is there
you can see the aberration which is
there it's very difficult to read
because they are very small print
so spherical aberrations recently I
started for doing for the last patient I
need about 30 patients so far very
collaboration and most of the machines
calculates at 6 millimeter I reduce it
to four millimeters own instead because
the when you read it the pupil is never
at 6 millimeter distance you always at
around 4 millimeter so you don't need a
spherical aberration which is 6
millimeter modifying the spherical
aberration to near 0 either point one or
point one on either side plus or minus a
4 millimeter zone when is whenever it is
possible in my machine I have a
limitations that in idak when I can't go
inside and change the various modes to
decide what exactly I want to do it so I
have a limited access to the technology
in matok platform improve depth of focus
significantly in all the 330 patients in
the aged between 23 and 25 here also I
suggest the beginning of a new concept I
am going to start with the older patient
now to prove what I am doing it it is
done with nitric platform which does not
allow to change the spherical
aberrations all the patients this is one
patient I have almost all the patients
with the similar to that here you see
the blue is the left eye we did on a
platform of cat that is a topo link we
could manage to get the spherical
aberration around that the first value
is well the Q value and the second one
is something which is either one I don't
remember which one is Q value other a
spherical aberrations and the red one is
the left which is done on our cats again
the same platform we could manage to
bring the spherical aberration nearby
zero and you see when you are putting a
zero it is six by four and then even if
you are changing 0.5 up to minus 3 it
maintains 6 by 5 vision that is what the
concept which is then the younger
patient now at present but probably this
will also help us to get a good
monovision the whole concept of Buono
vision will be
but without reducing the distance region
for one eye this is one new concept
which is there probably by next day we'd
be able to get the complete idea even in
the older patients so to conclude I am
NOT claiming at present anything because
it's still under the evaluations and we
have about two or three hundred patients
by next year depth of focus for distance
is a very good tool to evaluate
performance of any iron surgeon must do
all the depth of focus for all the
multifocal lessons to find out which
company has the best quality over here
but so more important for this course is
that in lesyk patient this could be a
very good tool to enhance the near
vision instead of going for a mono
vision thank you so much thank you I see
this is a very good work and original
work being done with the Indian
population I now invite the next speaker
dr. g'wan Lodi to talk about the
surgical technique and the post-op
management
thank you dr. sushi
respected seniors teachers and dear
friends
I think dr. Kaku you might be able to
help us in something where you can
enhance this depth of focus on his his
own machine okay we'll talk to them
later retracted surgical techniques and
post-op management there's no financial
interests examiner procedures in lassic
basically is called as a lizard in
Sedgwick error analysis and surface
ablation name will depend upon how the
epithelium is removed if you are you
mean by blade it's called a spear kpr we
mean by alcohol is called as a lassic
and if you are Ramin by a machine it's
called as a blessing a seer on surface
abrasion is nothing but the use of multi
my sincere 0.2% with chill balanced salt
solution and use of bandage contact lens
a say what we do is we put proper again
four to five times which will loosen the
epithelium before the procedure we use
20% alcohol in eight point five
millimeter cup which is kept for 20
seconds epithelium is peeled off easily
thorough chilled BSS wash is given then
you do laser after laser again chill BSS
washes given you apply the mitomycin c
for twenty to thirty second depending
about the refractive error again you
give a thorough chilled basis wash you
know put antibiotic bandage contact
lenses care for three to five days
post-op treatment is vitamin C for 15
days analgesic if required substrates
steroids are started up to 48 hours tap
at over a period of four to six weeks
antibiotic for eight days and lubricants
for six to eight weeks
lassic has different type a simple
lassic and you can have a front optimize
elastic where front guide a classic FEM
to listen lassie can relax my or flex
now I think we have a micro curtain pass
that is if you are using a blade I Ibiza
raised to sixty millimeter of mercury
and it causes a blackout temporal to the
patient swipe the stoma after the
abrasion is over a remove the excess
fluid do laser we posit the flap your
BSS wash under the flap and drying is
kept for two minutes antibiotics abide
for one week lubricants for four to six
weeks use of cyclosporine zero point
my person for six to twelve months for
previous irani trying i out of chronic
contact lens wearers in lassic what does
it do it treats the refraction but it
acts a spherical and higher-order
abrasions
we are from optimize lassic creates a
Spanish ship it treats the refraction
and treats the spiracle abrasions there
is no use of an ax Brahma tur we are
from guided lassic you need to have a
barometer it's a customized it reads the
refraction spherical aberration
higher-order abrasions and you have a
barometer and iris registration and
pupil central shift compensation is
required this is just to show you when
the ablation is going on what you can
see is the Sacketts the eyes moving
continuously and this is where the
active eye tracker is used which is
basically three dimensional system and
which detects the movements of the eye
in horizontal and vertical axis and
shift the ablation accordingly I will
not go into the detail of that relation
I uses a patient interface for talking
IOPS less than 30 to 40 millimeter of
mercury
there's no blackout so patient can keep
on seeing the target light till the end
and there are four planes fanta laser
cut is their anterior posterior side cut
an incision they said lenticular and
remove interface wash gentle massage for
the epithelial side from the Beatles I
use antibiotics to ride for one week
lubricant for four to six weeks an array
in cyclosporine as I told you before for
the lassic this is our one technique
which is called a safe that sharing a
bed force extraction and you will see
that basically it's a series of air
bubbles which are created by the
franchisor which is doing a first was to
be recut and then it does the interior
cut and the side cut we take two
millimeter incision at 110 degrees so
this session is little bit easier so in
this technique of safe that is sharing a
pair for succession what we do who first
locate the anterior plane and the
posture plane so dissect a little bit in
to enter plane and post a plane so
have two planes ready with you and you
can detect accordingly now keep the
hydration well during the procedure
so the cornet doesn't get dried up and
you don't get a speaker's
postoperatively and this is what we do
that minimal decision go to the opposite
side of the wound and dissect 180 degree
then left half and right half is
dissected and we are now above the
lenticular we call this as a lintel
pressurized assertion that is we press
onto the lenticular more while
dissecting so the surrounding stroma is
not disturbed much the inflammation is
less now we are going into the posterior
plane we just send clear of the central
area and don't break the lenticular at
this present stage but once that is done
then what we can see is now we have
broken the lenticular and we have cut on
all three quadrants except for the left
para central control and that is taken
out class this is what is called as a
safe now I put hydrate again put a fluid
inside give vertical and horizontal
massage so basically it's a created a
border which is created by the air
bubble when I give a massage they are
ironed and you will see that more than
95% the patient are 6x9 partial or
better within two hours of the surgery
this is the advantage of safe technology
which was devised by us we our friend
laser basically instead of refreshing a
map is treated so what you see here is a
having a refraction higher/lower
abrasions and this is what the map is
seen so this is the map and what is the
aim basically this is the this is the
map and which is a point spread of
function we want to convert this map
into a dot onto the macula so your
vision becomes more crisp and this is
one gives you a better vision than 6x6
and so called as a eagle vision or
something better than normal but a basic
idea is to convert a map into a spot
which will give you a clear-cut vision
on a Makarov a freaking Isle basically
for high myopia and where lassic is
contraindicated the USP Africa Kyle is
that the optic zone gives 1.25
magnification at nodal point of the eye
this is why the quality of vision of a
Kyle is better compared to any corneal
refractive procedure in addition to that
you are likely to get improvement in the
vision because of the magnification
factor if you see that loading of ISIL
is the most important part and it is
exactly opposite of the Isle which we
use for a cat eye surgery here once you
load the lens the cartridge remains
stationary and your forcep moves so you
you know the you can see that the
cartridge is at one place it is
stationary and it's a force F which is
moving whenever you are putting the
aisle in a cataract surgery we have
habit of taking the cartridge little bit
up for the aisle to go inside here
exactly opposite
keep your cartridge all the time
horizontal and don't move it at all so
keep patience this is going to unfold
slowly being a polymer material its
unfolds very slowly and see to it that
it folds and unfolds onto the iris so
see to it that you know your cartridges
all the time horizontal and don't come
out till the time last part goes in okay
so this is the most important step now
we can put the flags of the haptic
behind the iris which are technically
can use which are instrument you can use
this is the specific instrument for that
now you can see that there's a hole into
the center and you can see that visco is
coming out so don't press onto the optic
part but you can press onto the little
bit onto the edge of the optic so that
more fluidly come out so this stage
needs a little bit more patience spend
as much time as possible for removal of
Pisco and you will not find the IP spike
postoperatively thanks a lot Thank You
Jeevan our next speaker is the keynote
address and it's a very interesting
topic refractive surgery in children
thank you for welcome thank you my great
friend for having me in this prestigious
meeting giving me great opportunity so
in to strengthen the bond of the Indian
collaboration scientific issues so my
talk today about one of the most crucial
and controversial subject in
ophthalmology and we are the refractive
surgeons always struggling with the
pediatric of Talmadge's about this to
leave our patients with unilateral high
error and an isometric with their
glasses for a life or Toronto
diffractive surgery so starting by with
this consideration the laser vision
correction when mentioned it means
always unilateral procedure never
bilateral and quick introduction about
them is an isotropy it's a condition
with there is a difference of refraction
between both eyes with more than or
equal to two adapters either myopic
hyperopic or anti metropic in which the
patient or the child get one eye myopic
and the other eye is hyper metropic the
treatment options should be in this
order the spectacles the first line then
the contact lenses if available and
tolerable and then
shifting to diffractive surgeries
including the laser Laser laser
coordinate effective surgeries and
difficult the aim of treatment is for
the prevention and treatment of the
nitramene Tropea and insane subsequently
the anisotropic amblyopia
the amblyopia simply means that the eye
and the brain doesn't I don't don't work
in harmony the the there's nice
connection between the eye and the brain
and the eye is typically normal a while
to imply obeah the difference between
the both eyes visual a key of two lines
or more actually the amblyopia the most
common preventable cause of visual loss
in children so we are a need for
awareness programs for parents and as
well as the ophthalmologists stages of
treatment which I respect in all my
words the first stage should be the
glasses only the glasses correction
either default correction or the partial
correction till reaching the full
correction together with the patching of
the sound I to enhance and stimulate the
lazy one and this state in in my study
I followed four complete six months of
the full correction by the spectacle and
patching together starting the patching
for one one hour one hour per day for
one month in one and a half hours two
hours two and a half up to four hours
per day during the build of the
follow-up then the second stage will be
the refractive surgery and patching
after this surgery the contact lens when
when I got a patient with with good
Terrance and good behavior with the
contact lens I will left
him to complete but actually in this
ages it's so dangerous and so risky for
the this a children to wear the contact
lens because of the they may miss me set
or got infected corneum its prospective
study a Tito children include in this
study first and then just eleven be out
from this study because of the they were
not compliant with the protocol of this
study so I executed them
so the remains have anyone divided into
twelve patients completed with classes
because they showed a good correction
for their vision and and weather
response and the God responds with the
patching to what remained fifty mind
patients went for refractive surgery the
fifty nine patients with mean age of
seven point three years we are under gun
the corny refractive procedures
including lasik film to LASIK and PRK
for treatment of that condition the
preparation in the fall examination the
preparation with the psychological
fraction uh needing the best corrected
using the spleen and the chart the Penta
camp and this image shows have this
child with four point five years could
be compliant on capturing the Penta camp
in our Center and then the miserable
people imagery to consider the pupil
size and the optical zone correction
the procedures where as as follows LASIK
in 39 eyes film to LASIK in 6 eyes and
PRK and three eyes and if easier was
topical anesthesia most mostly but I
used general and teasy in in the
children who wear under four years
because they wouldn't be cooperative and
also the post-operative post-operative
care like that and the normal the normal
LASIK patients these are small videos
from the my procedures how to hand the
flap and how to use the suction ring on
the low vacuum technique to support a
globe in case of the generalities yeah
and in the topical and visa was with
uncooperative child after creation of
the flap they will leave the suction
ring in place under the low vacuum
technique to support the eye and trying
to centralize it then removing the flap
and budget an aside and then after laser
ablation
I will repository this patient this
child was eight years so so she was
cooperative and there were no there was
no need for this section rank
and PRK with echo assisted epithelial
removal to get a smoother surface and
easier epithelia removal with use of the
might imagine the old cases for 20
seconds so we are waiting for the
results of that work the which the
results means correction of vision
responds to patching and correction of
squint results were been gone the type
of the error or refraction my epics
should marvelous improvement even either
spherical or compound astigmatism and
makes it a stigmatism to the high probes
should less improvement my epics the
presence type and duration of squint
also also a very great and important
factor in the results the squint was in
twenty nine patients with east Rabia and
27 and esotropia in just to the type of
fixation either centric fixation in
twenty five and eccentric in just four
so all these factors are very important
and the results of that work also it's
surprising correction really gained
lines were much more than expected the
game lines again lines were four point
six with this standard deviation lines
but with eccentric fixation they should
longer slower and limited correction the
refraction was table with a increasing
improvement of the visual acne
throughout the full uh period patching
not needed in six children they showed
marvelous improvement more than six
twelve unaided in others it showed
private hopeful progress no significant
complications were reported in all
groups so i can conclude with these
tables
that only to Venus X of cases with
twenty needed adjuvant surgery patient
complete of the glasses showed at their
most achievement best corrected more
than mystic rated sorry it's more than
six twelve and sixty percent and so
after two weeks of the laser vision
correction the unaided post-operative
visual active was four point seven
increased lines and gaining lines with
the century fixation as above gaining
horizon eccentric with fixation what
much list was what one point three so at
the end of the follow appeared with six
months after patching they gain 5.3 as
above the center fixation and much less
two point four in with eccentric
fixation okay we'll have just a minute
to show examples of surprising cases of
this work this this cute girls
five-year-old with right hi Maria and
pics Atropa the right eye refraction was
- eight - it's fear - two-cylinder the
lift I was plus one with glasses in
fetching for six months she she had
missed corrected visual active 160 just
two weeks after LASIK I need the visual
equity was 660 really
six months after patching the on visual
on ear unaided visual active was six
mine the exotropia is corrected from
forty prison doctors to 20 as shown
these figures
this is preoperative and this is
post-operative after six months the
second case four years old girl right
high myopia a left eye is okay right was
-6 and also the same with patching and
the glasses missed great about 360 after
6 months 2 weeks after LASIK unaided was
666 month after pay with matching the
unaided pekin becomes 6 12 6 18 the
extra be almost corrected from 45 to 15
as shown this is B operatively and post
operatively the most the last surprising
ladies please conclude the most
surprising case 16 years old girl if the
embryo picked sue no scrunchie she was
not glasses glasses reader so the
unaided visual acti two weeks after lift
LASIK is 6 306 despite the best
corrected visual act was 460 and her age
is out of the common ages of correction
so we were so happy and surprised with
this unexpected results age refraction
Dame's amblyopia so the conclusion a
nasal trivia is a common cause of
amblyopia I do recommend laser vision
correction for treatment of anisotropy
and I believe if primary optical methods
have failed after adequate plan in a
certain time not more than one year I
have found it a very satisfactory and
safe procedure
so to my click please don't hesitate to
take your valuable under critical
decision at the suitable time and
following the ethics and evidence-based
medicine and thank you very much thank
you so for very less looked at area of
treating children especially in these
cases I have a question and if others
before that we have dr. Regina
now who has a very large experience in
this country in refractive and corneal
surgery and while he sets up there's a
how do you ensure fixation in small
children during the procedure the
defects Asians simply by the the you
mean the eccentric and eccentric how do
you ask the patient a child to look into
the fixation during surgery Nia you're
in surgery yeah okay either the people
either the child shows cooperation from
the start one table of the Machine and
and pie by the the kinda link and by the
patient's with him will follow the light
I will show fixation by the people mark
as usual in the end older patients in
the other lasik you will short fixation
when the patient is looking at the green
light in a excel crate of machine one
thing will fix it the green dot all the
time so if I could find that I will
complete otherwise I will I will use the
suction ring under the low vacuum
technique to centralize to help
centralization and the fixation and
capturing the image by the machine
itself thank you can you tell me
something about this low vacuum because
we I don't think is BK another machine
has got dr. it do you have something
like low vacuums of this is picking any
of this machine because how do you how
do you get your vacuum which carrot Omar
you using I'm using the Moriya the
Mauryan machine which one because they
speak and I we do not have any we don't
have a setting on sbk for low back so
how do you get low not so I speak a did
the common the other marine machine
which is commonly used in the the micro
curtam the microphone not the SPK
can you enlighten some the previous
version of the as
Laurium machines
yeah do you have that concept of low
vacuum on of any of this okay I think we
let it leave it that thank you so
forward the the normal vacuum used how
what's the normal vacuum used in the
lasik cases with Maria the machine which
reads I think it is around 700 600 yeah
I'm going down to four can you do that
yeah thank you thank you yeah okay sign
up please thank you to the Kapoor it's a
great pleasure to be here in this
wonderful course and I'll be talking
about a few things about corneal Hayes
after surface ablation a little bit
about regression after lassic so surface
ablation means PR que las sake alcohol
assisted or a people is lasers he do
create emilio says and all these things
have evolved because we have seen haze
in PR k over the years it has been seen
that haze can be seen in PRP and this is
something it looks like this is the
typical appearance of a suburb ethereal
haze and the risk factors can be higher
ablation high refractive error
correction retreatment previous coronal
surgery poor ocular surface and and and
basically it is the exaggerated corner
healing response and it is actually the
the interaction between the inflammatory
mediators of the tear film and the
character size that results in
fibroblast formation and that results in
a haze so his can be transient it which
normally appears between one to three
months postoperatively and it resolves
mostly over a period of a year and
patient patients usually are not with
much symptoms and that is why the
clinicians are quite happy that okay
it's not a significant haze sometimes
you can have a late onset Connolly haze
which occurs later in a couple of months
and then can last for a longer period
and some Hayes's can remain like that
forever
so people have tried to quantify haze by
various methods by confocal microscopy
by shim plug densitometry and there can
be subjective grading also depending
upon the visibility of the structures
behind the haze and confer scan also has
been used to see the haze as you can see
here the in-between Kirito sites this
this is pre PRK of confocal microscope
and this is post PRK so in between
Kurata sites you can see this myofibril
blast fibroblast present so this
actually is a way to quantify hey the
basic idea is to to create a management
protocol so that you can you know say
that with this kind of a grade you have
to do this but but the best thing is
that you should try to prevent haze and
that is basically done in PRK by user
mitomycin c and we all are using it it's
in a bit cell mitosis and we use it
mostly there although there are various
concentrations that have been used point
zero two percent for two minutes for one
minute for 30 seconds point zero one
percent for 45 seconds all these things
have been used but mostly people use
point zero two percent for 30 seconds
and that is what we also follow and this
is what u.s. army study has recommended
that PRK with mitomycin c point zero two
percent for 30 seconds had no measurable
level of mitomycin c in blood and that
is why it is safe and it also results in
preventing haze to a great extent
although in spite of all that studies
have shown that nearly one third of
individuals they do have some degree of
corneal haze now some haze may not be
significant
clinically at that point of time in a
patient can have good six-six vision but
this haze may become significant once
this individual you know grows older and
has to undergo cataract surgery and
wants a premium i oh well in that case
this subtle haze can become significant
and can have a suboptimal outcome with a
multi
Goliath now there are other agents like
topical steroid is something which is
very often used to prevent haze this is
I guess
apart from mitomycin c it is the steroid
that is that is most kuru Tinley used
for preventing haze high dose vitamin a
vitamin c all these things have been
used and have been found to be helpful
studies have shown proven efficacy of
all these now anti-vegf drug that is
Trico stat in a has been used
experimentally and normally what happens
that you know there is a tgf-beta 1 and
beta 3 for the healing response now the
T 1 has been shown to drive the corneal
criticized to differentiate into Maya
fibroblasts and T 3 inhibits the
fibrotic markers so if you can suppress
the T 1 stimulation by introducing T 3
that can prevent haze formation but this
is all experimental studies in vitro
studies and there have been have not
been used in human eyes as this study
shows that as I was mentioning earlier
also that one third of individuals do
have some amount of haze in spite of my
demise in CNS Corbett which may not be
significant clinically at that point of
time but later it may become significant
about the patient has to have a premium
aisle in the eye and what all these
modifications of surface ablation have
been shown even the trans epithelial PRK
the double stage 2 stage of one stage
all have shown some degree of haze with
with correction and if there is a haze
then that two three things that you can
do one is that you can do a superficial
debridement use topical mitomycin c you
can polish it with diamond bur it is
unfortunately I haven't put the video
I've done in case and it diamond bur has
been reused routinely for eg make season
when you remove the pterygium
whatever scar is there whatever
regularity on the cornea is there you
can polish and make it smooth and
regular by use of diamond bur
the same can be used in these cases and
of course you can do a PT k with
mitomycin c
so this was something about Hayes and a
little bit more that I've been asked to
present is about post lassic regression
now regression means you have corrected
an individual with lassic the refractive
correction has been done and now the
patient has come up after sometime after
months and years with some refractive
power requiring glasses requiring
contact lens and basically regression
has been shown to be caused by increase
in central epithelial thickness or they
can be a greater site hyperplasia Rabbit
trophy they can be a corneal forward
shift they can be Cohen elect a Jie so
all these can result in some degree of
kernel refractive regression after
refractive procedure and if you have a
regression because of the refractive
power coming in without any act Asia in
that case you can do you can relive the
flap and you can do a realistic now the
microcut at home flaps are easier to be
real IFTA Dan the femtosecond laser flap
because of obviously because of the of
the configuration of the peripheral part
of the flap now once you lift the flap
you can ablate it and you can deposit
the flap back
now surface ablation can also be done in
these cases because one application that
has been noted after realistic is
epithelial in growth and if if you find
that the flap is not lifting up easily
there's no point struggling and forcing
the flap to really lift you can go ahead
and do a surface ablation in order to
prevent the epithelial in growth because
of that and if you have done a
femtosecond lasik you can do a recut and
that you can do inside you can do with
there you can do a side cut within be
the initial flap and you can go ahead
and complete it so it's a vertical side
cut that is done
and you can lift another flap at the
same depth so and if you have a
regression because of because of Octavia
which can be seen you can have Octavia
because of higher ablation because of
you know in appropriate selection of
case because of some more factors which
perhaps we are not aware because
sometimes Octavia has been seen even in
conditions which were absolutely fit for
refractive procedure and they had
Octavia so the individual ocular surface
individuals mediators in the tear film
the hormonal changes all these things
can be factors that can lead to Octavia
in spite of you know taking all the
precautions and if there is Octavia in
that case you can do a RGB contact lens
fitting and that is the mainstay for any
clear case of Octavia it provides a very
good vision and if the patient is not
willing for contact lens fitting then in
Trapani ring segment is one good option
which can be tried in all these cases
now this is an example of a femtosecond
assisted in truck monitoring segment
implantation and
so what you normally do is that you
place the suction ring and a plane in
the cone application but then the other
that's fine that's fine and then the
vertical the radial incision is opened
up the initial part of the track is open
up this with this mechanical separator
and once you have done it and you can
place the inner corner ring segment and
once you have placed the internals in
segments you can debride the center part
of the epithelia within the ring segment
and you can do cross-linking so this is
one good option if the patient is not
tolerating contact-lens just one point I
would like to highlight here is that in
case of host classic Octavia it's better
most of the times they have a stigmatic
estimating errors so in those cases you
have to judge what type of ring segment
we have to use in order to correct
astigmatism in all these cases it's
better to use one segment or asymmetric
segments of internal ring segment thank
you very much
Thank You Rajesh is there any questions
our last but not the least speaker dr.
rohit shetty who is today training most
of the young ophthalmologist who and not
only a clinician but scientific
temperament by far in this country the
maximum and thank you Rohit sir for
joining us
there are some questions in this yeah
thank you sir thanks for this course
again this is I'll try to avoid any
repetition from what has already been
discussed so far these are my financial
interests my talk will go on this for
questions why do you need a PR k how do
you do a PR k controversies and demons
and what's the future the question why
is because we have different types of
topographies and not all topographies
which are suspicious are are exceed be
excluded sometimes we don't have a clear
picture sometimes it could be just a
variant of normal so avoiding LASIK for
somebody who's has a good topography but
it's a it's a small deviation may not be
the right way to do especially in that
era for having so many epithelial
changes and all those factors so PR k is
considered that way for many but in fact
in many places in the world it's the
first line of treatment that means if
you they don't even touch the refractive
procedure other than just mine so it's
better than the PRK so you can choose
that and how do you do it it depends on
how you take the epithelium off the
laces are just the same whether you do
an alcohol whether you do a manual
debridement I prefer now the last three
years a completely change is the all in
one short procedure the transpire case
now alcohol also has the same one but my
experience has been more with the
transparency of the shrimp so the second
question is how and why it should be
done this is where the big challenge
comes the whole idea of PRK is that is
more stronger more forgiving but we
still don't know the true picture so
because we don't know the true picture
the question still lingers so we did
this study this is the first of its kind
the most important thing in any
procedure is to see how the collagenous
unfortunately that not many technologies
which can evaluate or check the collagen
so this amazing the collagen completely
opened up a new avenue in understanding
and this is a custom built that means we
build this Oh City it's called the
polarization since the diversity works
on the principle of polarization it now
at this point of time it occupies the
whole room but eventually like all of
our cities will probably come smaller
than this laptop one day so how does it
look for the example this this is a
diagrammatic representation of how a
collagenous it's it has this strong
pillars in the in the periphery and you
can see the center is different oriented
this is how a collagen of your cornea so
when we image this this exactly what it
looks the blue area is different this is
your the those fibers at the periphery
and this is our normal collagenous so
it's important that the reason I'm
saying is this will help us to
understand what procedure and how it's
helping and this is how our orientation
that your what you call it as the
orientation of the fibers that's what
makes the cornea change that way so when
we look at patients who are don't have a
perfect topographies these are all
patients who don't have a perfect
topographies and you made the collagen
because topography is not the direct
link to what is happening in your
collagen and you can see that in this
case you can see that the completely the
collagen is completely low in this case
is a suspicious and you hardly see any
collagen this is normal this how a
normal should be but this case also
looks little suspicious but the collagen
is exactly the same as a pre-op so that
means there is so many variations in
this so what we did was we did the PRK
one i this was anyway normal we could do
the spine so we did the PRK and this
either I went into smile extra very
interesting find when you do any
cross-linking procedures with lasik it
should bring in strength the collage it
should look better or stronger but when
you do the same smile extra where you
pay a lot of money and you do a PRK the
collagen orientation is bang-on so that
means the PRK alone gives you the same
strength or more strength than a less
this is LASIK you can see that this
whole area out here it's weaker this is
a flap this is a flap and in PRK there's
no flat and you can see compare this
with normal the PRK eye after you do the
surgery actually becomes the collagen
orientation is much closer to a normal
than what you see in a lasik and a smile
extra is actually doing some benefit but
without doing any extra procedures you
are exactly getting the strength and in
this patient we did not do any surgery
so what we are trying to say is there's
tremendous amount of strength in PRK the
collage an orientation much well
preserved and when in doubt you should
remember this slide and this is just
going out to be a publications is a
first-of-its-kind when we are looking at
the collage and directly and you can see
the comparison between this the third
question is what are the demons the two
demons which we have in our in with us
when the plan is your pain the pain is
always a major factor and he is
beautifully covered by Raja sir this is
a paper which we published about using
the accueil activate I know the first
question you don't get a QL I've worked
with at least two companies now helping
them to develop it in the next two or
three months you'll get a preservative
freeze exactly the same activate which
can be used everywhere otherwise we had
to beg borrow or threaten the company
elegant to give us this drops much I
think it will just going to be used
freely so it makes this is how we do it
we just inject 0.2 ml like well we did a
lot of chromatography experiment to see
why we need to inject for 20 minutes
what is that because it needs to adsorb
why need to be covered everything the
lot of this question why not just soak
it because it takes that much time for
it to get adsorbed on the surface so
pain score is virtually nil now in my
practice so I have majority of my
patients offering PRT and they're
completely comfortable I usually do one
at a time just to see how the score is
and it's absolutely just like a normal
practice this been described by dr. Raja
sir but I just tell you this is a paper
with published in scientific reports
yes just a few months back what factors
really drive his and we had stored this
epithelium in our lab during the
procedure so when patients develop like
this yeah sorry his we had to go back to
the to artal to our same repository and
take those and figure it out so what we
found was this all this has been
explained there's a way use of for
healing changes of the patients who
developed his one of the major factors
was low vitamin D deficiencies a high
was di that means they were contact lens
intolerant and patient had huge amount
of ocular surface inflammation in terms
of mg D that means whatever was ocular
surface was actually the driving factors
how does it play a role all these things
including contact lens inter always play
important role in the corneal nurse and
these are your dendritic cells if the
nurse are hell unhealthy so your
response to healing is going to be very
unhealthy and it's going to create a
change this is exactly what happens so
what we did was we looked at all these
factors the OASDI vitamin d contact lens
intolerance the amount of gland loss you
have the working environment this is
very important in case of low late-onset
his most of the patients when they come
to me and they developed his liaisons
that i asked a question did you relocate
to a different place if you are staying
in Bangalore or a high-altitude place
and suddenly the patient goes and
relocates to Mangalore or Chennai or
some other place where there's more UV
light the trigger of factors could
change so one question is about change
in the position or sometimes they say
that I'm getting the LASIK surgery done
in Bangalore I'm staying for two months
and I'm going to relocate somewhere else
then I tell them you need you eat
glasses more frequently and baby built
this core which is just on the process
of validation and we call it as a
predictor perfect score which may be
looking at validating them which I'll
share with you some time and based on
the risk score we try to change the
medications
what type of drops we use how long we
use because we feel that these things
really help in getting much better
outcome especially when you're looking
at the haze as a factor and our
preoperative regimen also changes along
with the scale because one his patient
out of thousand is still a pain because
they
to make you feel loose interest in that
procedure and again intraoperatively
even the active ale works in the this
phase so even giving an early activate
the soaked contactless actually reduces
haze to some extent I've spoken about
mitomycin and B but when we did the
prospect e1 we were able to reduce it
much more than what we have and you have
now close to three years of data on this
so what do we get here is more safe and
predictable there is link of laser to
your biology which has been explained by
me and dr. Raja sir there's something
which is work in progress
and I still believe that it's one of the
strongest procedures and PSA OCT did
brew that clearly thank you
Thank You Roy first of all
congratulations for the extraordinary
work that you are doing any questions
maybe once was questioned everyone
question like for the Journal of
technologies who wants to become was to
go for the practice surgery what do you
advise that it should start with
ICL or if you start with LASIK and water
no matter what you will suggest us to
improvise his reflective dr. Pugh
another well and he wants to know if he
wants to start refractive practice
should he first do I see also first
LASIK pyaar ki professor see now yes
definitely I would agree pyaar ke will
be the simplest to do and we should you
should start with P okay do you want his
question is that whether he can start I
CLI think and start I see very wants to
start refractive practice should it be
with IC l or surface procedure or LASIK
it's easier I think it doesn't make any
difference almost all of them are same
because you have a different indications
for region and flap neck is not that
difficult I think as for a surgical
technique and safety is concerned
they're fine but the advantage of the
ICL is you probably already have the
infrastructure in place if you're
already doing cataract surgery so while
you wait to sort of set up or find a
place where you can start doing laser
ablation procedures at least with ICL
you can start I think with my young
colleague and I would go with PRK LASIK
and I see else after a year of getting
used to refractive surgery patients
thank you any other questions yeah can
you come to the mic please please ask
anything related to starting refractive
anything I so for the surface procedures
do oral steroids have any role in the
haze
we don't have a portable mic but Roy can
you just see I I don't think based on
studies we I mean there's no role of
oral steroids to prevent haze and for
the topical steroids even before the
epithelia ization is complete do we
start over the bandage contact lens
itself what we've usually been
practicing is once we remove the bandage
contact lens and we're sure that there's
no epithelial defect left after that we
start topical steroids absolutely
actually that's what is general practice
that once there is epithelial healing
after 48 to 72 hours you start steroid
there is one study which states that if
you start steroid before everything and
healing from day one a the incidence of
haze was less I mean that that is one
study which has compared and has stated
this thing but apart from that general
practice I think I mean we also follow
that that for 48 hours we we don't give
steroid and after that we start you are
right you don't start the steroid till
that bandied lenses off but I think you
know I if you're covering the patients
with your NSAIDs well then that is also
a factor even though I was slightly
differ on insist because if there's any
corneal surface defect anything then and
say should be avoided yeah so there lot
of views on this I don't do many PR K's
I do about three four hundred a year but
I start steroids from the immediately on
the table as soon as the procedure is
over I haven't had a problem in the last
three to four years before that I wasn't
doing PRK since recently it's coming to
you know fashion and so you start with
redness alone acetate or some low
anything it could be a drop PD a
combination of for any state actually I
would say that if you're using Pradesh
state what happens is there is a lot of
deposition and you have put a bandage
contact lens also so it's better to use
spread phosphate in those wherein you
have a clear solution all kinds of
refractive procedures we practically not
using any NS AIDS so is it really
recommended even whether it's lassic or
epi are
I was using like you will only the
contact will not not by the bandied
lengths or banded lines only for six
hours what you use is only for six hours
the venue so planned stuff again
no no it's not possible there's no end
said after six no no it's so that's why
you know we compared the the wound
healing I mean this is the first
question and the most of the issues
related with delayed or melt was more
from the altar and be the diclofenac the
accueil has some component that's why I
know it's a preservative free and we did
not see even in the paper we have
mentioned that was you know we did not
see any difference in wound healing
compared to the I which where it was it
was a plastic of it was not under the
deform so we are not loading it after I
think it's just the tip oh and it lasts
for we the deposition of fur this lasts
for six to eight hours whether the
maximum pain pain is basically for pain
well is there any harm in giving pain
relief for a lot more time with drops
maybe answer drop see the basic idea is
the pain related factors when you make
up the art a is maximum between the 6 to
12 hours so 0 to 12 us if you are able
to knock it off even if you use
continuous states of no use it's the
first 24 hours which is very much it yes
sir could you could you use the mic this
mic
about your question about the low vacuum
technique I brought it from the official
site of the Moorea Moorea is a the
Mauryan machine there is a button is
called low vacuum button the window
detected vacuum is 760 okay and the low
vacuum is down to 250 could be catching
the eye down to 250 which model Mori is
a not for s PK I would I can show it now
thank you it's just that most of us s PK
which is the current model in refractive
surgery so that option is not there on
the speaking thank you thank you very
much
last question I think the next guys have
come not a Christian sacrament with s BK
Maria if you wish to achieve low vacuum
you just puncher the line with a 26
gauge needle and the vacuum will drop
down by one third of one fourth
depending on the size of the gauge of
the needle you can achieve do a little
trial and error because I have been
doing many surface simulation under GA
and because many of the very
uncooperative patient at the age of
fifteen sixteen sometimes we do like sir
is doing you just puncher the line and
vacuum is broken to half or one third
thank you so thank you all the
participants and the audience thank you